据估计  可观察到的宇宙达到了93亿光年的距离范围
It's estimated the observable universe is 93 billion light-years across.
可能更确切地说
It's probably more accurate...
那里离这儿很远
I'm gonna be so far away.
我不在乎  我不想分手
I don't care. I don't want to break up.
周末我会去看你
I'll come on the weekends.
斯坦福在美国的另一边
Stanford's on the other side of the country.
我爸爸至少飞行了一千万里
My dad has, like, ten million frequent flyer miles.
他不会介意的
He won't care.
大家都在注意听吗
Are we all right over here?
呃  是的  达蒙先生
Uh, yes, Mr. Damon.
我刚刚只是呛到了
I just had something caught in my throat.
艾比  这里是不容许吃喝东西的
Abby, you know you're not supposed to have any food or drinks in here.
只是水而已
Oh, it's just water.
我有点咳嗽
I have a cough.
不想打扰别人
I didn't want to disturb anyone.
我们只能观察到宇宙的4%
We can only observe 4% of the universe.
剩下的还是未知的
The rest of it is unaccounted for.
我竟然不知道你这么会撒谎
I never knew you were such a good liar.
再喝点伏特加  你或许还会发现我的其他一些不为你所知的地方
Well, a little more vodka, and you might find out some more things you didn't know about me.
是吗
Really?
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
是  老师
Yes, sir?
从这些多得难以置信的星星中我们能得出什么结论呢
What conclusions can we draw from the incredible number of stars?
结论是这个电影要么非常好  要么很差
That the movie's either gonna be really good or really bad.
我更加注意的是有关外星生命的问题
I was thinking more about the implications for extraterrestrial life.
我想  若是有无数个星星的话
Well, I guess if there's an infinite number of stars,
可能除了太阳系外  至少还有一个星系上存在着生命体
Odds are there's at least one galaxy with life other than our own.
或者说
Or?
或者  没有
Or...not?
或者可以说  我们太阳系是很独特的
Or our solar system is somehow unique.
现在的问题是  "哪里独特呢"
The question then becomes, "In what way?"
现在的问题是
The question then becomes,
"你还能教我们些更无用的东西吗"
"Could you possibly teach us anything more useless?"
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
艾比
Abby?
哦  天哪  出事了  她没呼吸了
Oh, my god. Something's wrong. She's not breathing.
艾比
Abby?
打911
Call 911.
你能不能在你的果冻祝酒下面垫张餐巾纸呢
Would you mind at least putting a napkin under your jelly toast?
你弄张桌子来  我就不会在沙发上吃了
Get a table, and I won't eat it on the couch.
不  你还是会的
Yes, you will.
但我就不会有这么好的借口了
But I won't have a good excuse.
为什么你不去弄张桌子来呢
Why don't you go get a table?
又不是我的公寓
Not my condo.
我批准了
You have my permission.
挑你喜欢的任何东西都行
Pick out whatever you want.
那样就只能展现我的风格而不是你的
Then it would be a reflection of me, not you.
那样不好
That wouldn't be right.
不  那可以说明
No, it would be a reflection of the fact
那个一直赖着我的家伙
that the guy who's been mooching off of me
并不完全是忘恩负义之徒
for as long as I can remember isn't a complete ingrate.
你从没布置过一间房子
You've never furnished a home.
我布置过一堆的房子
I have furnished a bunch of homes.
不  你娶过一堆女人是她们布置的那些房子
No, you've married a bunch of women who furnished a bunch of homes.
你想搁在什么东西上吃是吧  没问题
You want to eat off something? Fine.
把你的钢琴搬过来  在那上面吃
Move your piano in here and eat off that.
你害怕
You're afraid.
怕一个餐桌吗
Of a dining table?
就算把床柱上的把手下下来安到餐桌上
You know, they don't actually come to life
它们也不会变成活物
when you put a knob off your bedpost on them.
你所处的环境就是一面镜子
You are what you sit in.
你的朋友  工作  家具
Your friends, your job, your furnishings--
都能映照出你的性格
It all defines you.
你其实并不相信这点
You don't really believe that.
你只是不想去购物罢了
You just don't want to do the shopping.
买些家具回来
Buy some furniture,
不然就承认  你内心很空虚
or admit that you're empty inside.
X光检查的结果证实了
X-rays confirm the fluid
那些差点让她窒息而死的液体是肺水肿引起的
that almost suffocated her to death was from pulmonary edema.
就是说问题出在她的心脏或肺上
Means the problem's either in her heart or lungs.
毒化检验显示只有酒精
Tox screen's clean for everything except the alcohol,
她的碱式氯化铝含量也只有0.05毫克
and her B.A.C. was barely .05.
说明她只喝了一两口酒  顶级的
That means she only had one or two drinks, tops.
而且也没有外伤的迹象
And there's no sign of trauma.
你怎么知道
How'd you know?
因为如果有的话
Because if there was,
卡迪就不需要我来接手这个病人了
Cuddy wouldn't have needed me to take the case.
-你怎么知道卡迪  -福曼是唯一一个
- How do you know Cuddy... - Foreman's the only one
敢不跟我商量就接任务的
with the balls to take a case without checking with me,
而他现在还在吃早餐
and he's still working on breakfast,
就说明那个
which means that the...
18岁
18...
不对  17岁的优等生
No, 17-year-old honor student--
卡迪对聪明的女孩
Cuddy has a soft spot
特别关照  他们到了大四下学期
for smart girls, and they don't start drinking
才开始喝酒
until second semester, senior year.
所以要么你认为聪明的女人
So either you think that smart women
彼此会互相照顾  这说明你是个白痴
look out for each other, which means you're an idiot,
或者你觉得卡迪不聪明  也就是说
or you think Cuddy's not smart, which means...
不过  这两种想法的结论都一样
Well, I guess it's the same both ways.
那你怎么
Then how did you...
照片从病历中掉出来了  她看上去很聪明
Picture fell out of the file. She looks smart.
-陶博在哪儿  -难道你不知道吗
- Where's Taub?  - You don't already know?
对  他在家和老婆吵架
Yeah, he's at home in a fight with his wife.
我只是好奇他会如何跟我解释
I'm just curious what he wanted me to know.
他的车爆胎了  他在等拖车
His car has a flat tire. He's waiting for a tow truck.
血压升高会不会是饮酒过度引起的呢
What about rising blood pressure from binge drinking?
那能引发高血压
It could set off a hypertensive crisis,
导致心力衰竭
cause heart failure.
两口酒怎能算过度
Two drinks is hardly a binge.
若是澳大利亚人肯定没问题
Certainly not if you're an aussie.
但若是美国女学生在早上10点前喝了两口酒
But when an American schoolgirl has two drinks before 10:00 a.M.,
那她肯定打算喝更多
it's a pretty sure bet that the plan is to have a lot more.
也许这不是她第一次这样做了
Probably wasn't the first time she had that plan.
我会做个c-13-丙酮酸磁共振成像
We'll get a c-13-pyruvate mri
检查她的心脏乳酸水平
to check for cardiac lactic-acid levels.
谁给陶博打个电话
Someone call Taub.
让他在私人时间处理掉他的老婆
Tell him to cut the ball and chain on his own time.
你和我吵架是因为夫妻瑜伽的事情吗
We're arguing about couples yoga?
不是
No.
问题在于我们从未一起做过什么事
We're arguing over the fact that we don't ever do anything together anymore.
难道我们从来没一起做过什么吗
We don't ever do anything together?
克里斯  我爱你  但我发誓
Chris, I love you, but I swear,
如果你再用这种审问证人的口气跟我说话的话
if you start talking to me like I'm on the witness stand again,
我会拧断你的脖子
I'm gonna break your neck.
亲爱的  我们一直都是一起做事的啊
Honey, we do stuff together all the time.
是吗  比如什么
Really? Like what?
除了睡觉  看电视  出去吃饭
Besides sleeping, watching tv, going out to dinner,
我们还一起做过什么
what do we do together,
就只我们两个
just the two of us?
我们
We...
你不喜欢出去吃饭吗
You don't like going out to dinner?
好吧  我会去练瑜伽的
All right, I'll do the yoga.
算了
Forget it.
你现在又不希望去练了
Now you don't want me to do it?
去上班吧
Just go to work.
不
No.
在我们解决这个问题前  我不会离开的
I'm not leaving until we work this out.
我没事  拜托  快走吧
I'm fine. Please, just go.
艾比·纳什在哪里
Where's Abby Nash?
我是尼克  是她男朋友
I'm Nick, her boyfriend.
这是我爸
This is my dad.
你可以等候在...
You can wait in...
她在哪
Where is she?
她还好吗
Is she okay?
她正在做检查
She's having some tests run.
她没事吗
Is she okay?
我们认为饮酒可能对她的心脏造成了损害
We think her drinking may have damaged her heart.
她的心脏吗
Her heart?
不  她不喝酒
No, she doesn't drink,
没喝很多
Not that much.
只在学校里喝吗
Just when she's at school?
尼克  怎么回事
Nick, what's he talking about?
一次旅行中  有个学生手里有假张身份证[用来买酒]
It was a field trip. One of the kids had a fake I.D.
不过  爸爸  你了解艾比的  告诉他
But, dad, you know Abby. Tell him.
我知道她的为人
Well, I know what she's like
你们在我面前时  她是怎么样的  不过...
When the two of you are around me, but...
如果你是对的检查结果会呈阴性
If you're right, The tests will come back negative.
你能帮我带个口信给她吗
Can you give her a message?
我帮她把作业拿来了
I brought her homework...
还有  我爱她
And I love her.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
尼克很爱你
Nick loves you.
豪斯不相信你的车爆胎了
House doesn't believe you got a flat tire.
他觉得我为什么迟到呢
What does he think I was doing?
和你妻子吵架
Fighting with the wife.
我为什么要说谎呢
Why would I lie about that?
她想让我和她一起练瑜伽
She wants me to do yoga.
我们要做更薄的层面剖析
We need thinner cuts.
当你和卡梅隆意见有分歧时
When you and Cameron had disagreements...
你向我咨询婚姻问题似乎不妥
I'm probably not the best guy to go to for marital advice.
对不起
Sorry.
只是...
It's just...
加强显示二尖瓣
Punch in to the mitral valve.
好了  我明白你的意思了
All right, I get the message.
不  不  我是认真的
No no, I'm serious.
那是什么
What is that?
可能是真菌感染
Could be a fungus.
急诊室做过血液培养了
E.R. Drew blood cultures--
都是阴性  没寄生虫  没真菌
All negative, no parasites, no fungus.
可能是肠道苛求菌
It could be fastidious enteric bacteria.
你觉得她吃了你妻子做的东西吗
You think she's been eating your wife's cooking?
嗨  我站在你这边  兄弟
Hey, I'm on your side, man.
我没在和我妻子吵架
I am not fighting with my wife.
我的车爆胎了  还放在我后备箱内
I had a flat tire. It's in my trunk.
你可以自己去看
You can go look at it if you want.
不需要
Don't need to.
表情告诉我你在说虚张声势
Face tells me you're bluffing.
不是你的  是奇斯的表情
Not yours...chase's.
如果她有肠道感染她会表现出肠道症状
If she was infected through the intestinal tract, she'd have intestinal symptoms.
肠道细菌还可能通过其它方式获得并进入血液
There are other ways to get enteric bacteria into the bloodstream.
她不静脉注射吸毒没有纹身
She's not an intravenous drug user, she has no tattoos,
并且她身上没任何伤疤能说明她会自残
And she doesn't have any scars that would indicate she's a cutter.
做个经食管超声心动扫描
Transesophageal echo could give us a better idea
会为我们提供更多线索
Of what we're looking at.
如果瓣膜快要裂开
If that valve is about to dehisce,
心动描记会引发心脏病发作
Echo could trigger a heart attack.
那你们想个更好的主意或是准备好急救推车
So come up with a better idea Or have a crash cart ready.
你为什么对豪斯说谎
Why are you lying to House?
奇斯告诉我了  有什么大不了的呢
Chase told me. What's the big deal?
我们换个时间聊这个吧
Maybe we can talk about this another time...
或永远不谈
Or never.
我想她不会告诉别人的
I really don't think she's gonna tell anyone.
如果我承认我们在吵架他就会想知道为什么
If I admit we're fighting, He's gonna want to know what about.
那就告诉他真相呀
So tell him,
或者告诉他不要多管闲事
Or tell him it's none of his business.
说谎更容易
This is easier.
真的吗  看起来比说实话难多了
Really? Because it seems much harder.
我知道什么  我又不是男的
What do I know? I'm not a guy.
对...
Yes...
除非我能像你一样坦露自己感情
If only I could be as open about my emotional life as you are.
这件事与瑜伽无关
It's not about the yoga.
真的吗  我还以为有关呢
Really? I thought it was,
因为我们讨论了一个小时瑜伽
Since we spent an hour talking about yoga,
不过我怎么知道呢  我不是女的
But what do I know? I'm not a girl.
我猜她认为你不愿花时间和她待在一起
My guess is she thinks you don't want to spend time with her
而是花时间陪在别人身边
Because you're spending it with someone else.
如果她觉得我有外遇  她会问的
If she thinks I'm cheating, she would ask.
因为你总是说实话吗
Because you'd tell the truth?
我确实没有外遇
I'm not seeing anyone else.
那不管  你有前科
Doesn't matter. You have a history.
那不是她的错
And that's not her fault.
那我该做什么呢
So what am I supposed to do?
我不能证明不存在的事情
I can't prove a negative.
这确实是个问题
That is a problem.
心脏在这里
There's the heart.
瓣膜看上去正常
Valves look fine--
没有赘生物  没有粘液性变性
No vegetations, no myxomatous changes.
你能给她多打一点点镇静剂吗
Can you give her a little more sedative?
主动脉夹层正在破裂
She's dissecting.
已经撕裂了  把探头拿出来
She's rupturing. Get the scope out.
完全不合理
This doesn't make sense.
她的血压正常  心率也控制得很好
Her b.P. Is normal, and her heart rate was controlled.
过会再找原因
We'll figure it out later.
我们只剩大概30秒钟的时间打开它的胸腔
We've only got about 30 seconds to get her open.
插管处没有渗漏
No leakage from cannulation site.
很好
Nice.
看看她心脏能否重新跳动
Let's see if she'll start up.
除颤器
Cardiac paddle.
充电
Charging.
放电
And go.
加油
Come on.
再来一次  放电
Again. Go.
5毫升肾上腺素
Pushing five ccs Adrenline.
再来一次
Zap her again.
不要
No.
这没用的  闪开
It's not working. Clear.
闪开
Clear.
正常窦性心律
Normal sinus rhythm.
感谢上帝
Thank god.
经食管超声心动扫描和手术中所见没有发现瓣膜上有赘生物
T.E.E. And intra-operative visualization showed no vegetations on the valves,
没有结构异常
No structural abnormalities.
主动脉夹层说明我们之前
The dissection means we were wrong
关于酒精引起高血压危象的猜测错误
About alcohol causing a hypertensive crisis.
你说"我们"  其实是"你"
And by "We" You mean "You."
是啊  但你也没有更好的主意啊
Yeah. You were the one who didn't have any better ideas.
又不是我的过错
It's not my fault.
我当时还忙着评价陶呢
I was busy trying to judge Taub.
既然我们排除了外伤的可能性
Since we already ruled out trauma,
主动脉夹层可能是遗传缺陷
The dissection's probably a genetic defect.
我们在做测试
We're running the tests.
她不是马凡氏综合征患者
She's not marfanoid.
那过敏呢
What about an allergy?
严重的过敏症状可以触发系统性的免疫反应
A severe enough one could set off a systemic immune reaction,
进而导致肺部积液
Cause fluid in the lungs,
还有炎症会削弱主动脉
And inflammation that could weaken the aorta.
如果是过敏的话
If it was an allergy,
她在医院里就会有所好转
She'd be getting better in the hospital,
-而不是更严重了  -除非是过敏源在她体内
- Not worse. - Unless it was inside her.
意味着
Meaning?
你们要我的精子
You want my sperm?
我们认为严重的过敏反应能导致系统性的崩溃
We think a severe allergic reaction could be causing systemic breakdown.
对我儿子的精子过敏吗
To my son's sperm?
事实上更可能是他的精液的问题
Actually, his semen is more likely the problem,
所以我觉得你刚才的反应对象并不对
Which, I realize, is not what you were reacting to.
你们上一次进行没有防护措施的性爱是什么时候呢
When's the last time the two of you had unprotected sex?
从没有  我用避孕套的
Never. I use a condom.
你时刻都用避孕套吗  所有过程吗
You always use a condom... for everything?
对大多数过程
Well, for most everything.
什么时候
When?
她崩溃的前一晚
The night before she collapsed.
我会滴一滴尼克的精液蛋白到你皮肤上
I'm placing a drop of Nick's semen protein onto the skin.
然后我会用枕头来摩擦
Then I'll abrade it with a needle,
一个小时左右来检查皮疹
Check for a rash in an hour or so.
妈妈  得了吧
Mom, come on...
我们都约会了三年了
We've been dating for three years.
我没有生气  亲爱的
Look, I'm not mad, sweetheart.
我只是困惑了
I'm just confused.
系统性的反应可能是由精液蛋白引发的
A systemic reaction Can be triggered by the protein in semen.
在多数情况下  这种反应是相当微小的
In most cases, the reaction is fairly minor.
但在少数情况下反复暴露在过敏源下会引发过敏反应
But in rare cases, Repeat exposure can trigger a hypersensitivity response.
反复暴露吗
Repeat exposure?
我懂  我懂
Ugh, I know, I know--
三年时光
Three years.
这会疼的吗
Is it supposed to hurt?
反应时间应该长于
The reaction should take longer than...
不是那里
No, it's not that. Ow.
-艾比  怎么了  -我的胃
- Abby, what's wrong? - My stomach.
血尿
Blood in the urine.
救命
Help me!
没有过敏反应
No allergic reaction.
另一方面  她的肾脏现在正在衰竭
On the other hand, now her kidneys are failing.
会是某种神经性病变吗
Could be some kind of neuropathy.
梅毒性的闪电痛吗
Syphilitic lightning pains?
不是梅毒
It's not syphilis.
性病研究实验室和酶免疫测定都是阴性
Vdrl and enzyme immunoassays were negative.
那血栓呢
What about a blood clot?
她做完动脉手术要用抗凝剂的时候你考虑血栓吗
While she's on anticoagulants from the aortic surgery?
间质性肾炎呢
Interstitial nephritis?
不会引起水肿和主动脉夹层
Wouldn't cause the edema or dissection.
但是癌症能解释通
But cancer could.
你敢说得再具体一些吗
Would you care to be a little more specific?
如果我知道的话  我早就说了
If I could, I would have.
我们可以给她做个全身扫描
We could do a full-body scan.
我们讨厌全身扫描
We hate full-body scans.
你说"我们"  其实是"你"
And by "We" You mean "You."
我们同样讨厌病人病故
We also hate when a patient dies
在我们能搞清楚他们到底出了什么问题前
Before we figure out what's wrong with them.
去做全身扫描吧
Do the scan.
你怎么去说服别人你没有欺骗他们呢
How can you convince someone you're not cheating on them?
真的别欺骗就行
Don't cheat.
过段时间后  他们会知道真相的
After a while, they'll catch on.
假若我不想等那么久呢
What if I don't want to wait that long?
无论你去哪  带他们全天24小时和你一起
Take them with you wherever you go for 24 hours a day.
是的  你老婆有不安全感
So your wife's a little insecure.
又那么糟糕吗
Is that so bad?
至少你知道她还关心这些
At least you know she still cares.
我知道她很关心
I know she cares.
我需要的是让她开心起来
What I want is for her to be happy.
怎么了
What?
你觉得我不想让我老婆开心吗
You don't think I want my wife to be happy?
当然觉得
Sure...
只要那能让你开心
As long as it makes you happy.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
我觉得你动作迅速
I think you work quickly.
小事一桩
Piece of cake--
你付钱  他们给家具
You give them money, they give you furniture.
还不错吧
Not bad, huh?
不是
Nope.
是一点坏的感觉都没有
It's not bad at all.
花的时间有些长啊
It's taking a really long time.
再忍受一会除非有必要  你最好忍住别说话
Just hang in there and try not to talk unless you really have to.
那会影响到成像的
It can affect the images.
那是什么
What was that?
喂  你还在吗
Hello? Are you still there?
我觉得这仪器有些问题
I think there's something wrong with the machine.
不是仪器的问题
It's not the machine.
是地震而已
It's an earthquake.
抓住  我们来把你弄出来
Hold on. We'll get you out.
现在就把我弄出去
Get me out now.
哦  天哪
Oh, my god!
我抓不住了
I can't hold on!
是黑洞
It's a black hole.
她产生了幻觉
She's hallucinating.
我确实希望如此
I certainly hope so.
(你在哪?)
豪斯
House!
这不好玩
It's not funny.
我的问题已经够多了
I got enough problems already.
相信我吧  这会有帮助的
Trust me. This is gonna help.
动脉瘤能解释幻觉
An aneurysm explains the hallucinations.
而且这点是我们在鉴别诊断时没有排除的
And it's the one thing We haven't excluded from the differential.
你的短信不能证明你的忠诚
Your texting does not prove you're faithful.
只能说明你知道  她觉得你不忠
Just proves you know she thinks you're unfaithful.
信任不能被强加
Can't force trust.
她幻觉了什么
What did she hallucinate?
幻觉的内容不相干的
The content of the hallucination isn't relevant.
-通常不是  -从不想干
- Not usually. - Not ever.
我们什么都不知道  大脑却什么都知道
We know nothing. Brain knows all.
得了溃疡  你不会知道
You get an ulcer, you don't know it,
但是大脑增加黏液素分泌
But the brain increases mucin secretions.
它知道出了什么问题
It knows what the problem is,
哪里有问题
Knows where the problem is.
从机体免疫反应到大脑给予下意识诊断线索
It's a big logical jump from a body's immune response
这在逻辑上可是个大跳跃
to the brain giving subconscious diagnostic clues.
梦到瀑布  水流什么意思
What about dreaming about waterfalls, running streams
得去洗手间吗
if you need to go to the bathroom?
没错  就像是大脑呼喊
Sure. That's the same as the brain shouting,
"你有胰腺癌"
"You have pancreatic cancer."
她的潜意识试图告诉她什么
Her subconscious is trying to tell her something.
我们得偷听
We need to eavesdrop.
她尖叫说她被吸进黑洞
She was screaming she was being sucked into a black hole,
那么我们是不是该在她的肛门里找肿瘤呢
So we should look for a tumor in her anus?
我们需要完整的故事
We need the whole story.
认知模式识别
The cognitive pattern recognition program
或许能告诉我们她的脑袋里发生了什么
might tell us what's going on in her head.
或许  我们可以基于科学做点什么而不是根据科幻小说
Or we could act on something based in science, not science fiction.
做个对比磁共振血管造影看看她有没有动脉瘤
Get an MRA with contrast to see if she has an aneurysm,
除非你觉得卡迪会支持读心术
Unless you think Cuddy's gonna go for the mind reading.
算了  磁共振血管造影
Fine. Do the MRA.
等结果出来是阴性的时候  我们能转向
When it comes back negative, we can move on to the...
疯狂  不过也许能有用的主意
Crazy but possible ideas.
你怎么处理了那些家具
What did you do with the furniture?
退了
I returned it.
你让我买下的
You told me to buy it.
不过你没有  你仅仅是租的
But you didn't buy it. You rented it.
你给经济家具供应打了电话
You made one phone call to economy furniture supply--
"我们搞定  不用你忙"
"We get it done so you don't have to."
那又怎样  我们有了桌子  椅子
So what? We had a table, chairs--
但是看不出任何意义
But no clue what any of it meant.
好了  我雇个装璜师
Fine. I'll hire a decorator.
棒极了  另一个女人来告诉你你是谁
Perfect. Another woman to tell you who you are.
我雇个男的装璜师
I'll hire a male decorator.
你要走进一家家具店
Step inside one furniture store
找件你喜欢的东西
And find one thing you like.
我喜欢不这么做
I like not doing this.
一件
One.
艾比
Abby.
你好
Hi.
我妈妈在哪里
Where's my mom?
她下去买早饭了
She went down to get some breakfast.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
还行  除了我差不多没法呼吸还有浑身疼
Well, besides the fact that I can barely breathe and I ache all over,
不太妙
Not good.
我能做什么吗
Anything I can do?
就是别走
Just don't go.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
距离我们上一次超过一天没干那个很久了
Been a while since we've gone more than a day without doing that.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
你说什么
What'd you say?
我在想
I've been thinking.
距离我们上一次超过一天没干那个很久了
Been a long time since we went more than a day without doing that.
我们有个秘密
We have a secret.
现在  你不用马上回答  不过
Now, you don't need to answer right now, but...
艾比  我想娶你
Abby, I want to marry you.
告诉他那个秘密  没事的
Tell him the secret. It's okay.
不对劲
Something's wrong.
-什么  -艾比  你觉得怎样
- What? - Abby, what are you feeling?
我不知道
I don't know.
你的秘密在杀死你
Your secret is killing you.
我看见  或许都是因为药
I see, um... maybe it's all the medication.
我就是
I'm just--um...
艾比  你能听到我说话吗
Abby. Can you hear me?
你该死
You deserve to die.
我们需要4毫克劳拉西泮
We need four milligrams lorazepam.
她癫痫发作超过一分钟
She seized for over a minute.
发作期脑电图显示没有同步放电
Inner-ictal E.E.G. showed no synchronous discharges.
磁共振血管造影呢
And the MRA?
没有动脉瘤  脑部动脉或静脉无异常
No aneurysms or arterial or venous malformations in the brain.
意料之中
As predicted.
我们说要继续做什么来着
What did we say we'd move on to?
灵魂出窍能被
Out-of-body experiences can be induced
颞顶联合区感觉超负荷所诱导
by sensory overload in the temporoparietal junction.
核磁共振上颞顶联合区无异常
Temporoparietal junction was clean on MRI,
还有磁共振血管造影  全身扫描
MRA, and whole-body scan.
就只留给我们一个疑问
Which just leaves us with the question
灵魂出窍时到底发生了什么
Of what happened during the out-of-body experience.
要是我说她的血压飙至200多她还咬了自己的舌头
If I say her blood pressure shot up over 200 and she bit her tongue,
是个满意的答复吗
Would that be a satisfactory answer?
当然  要是你接着回答
Sure. If you then went on to answer the following--
她的灵魂有没有漂浮于身体之上呢 见到上帝了吗
Did she float above her body? Did she see Jesus?
她是否在恒河沐浴呢
Did she bathe in the ganges?
没有  没有还是没有
No, no, and no.
我们能不能回到医学上来
Can we get back to the medical science?
不行
No.
她声称以年轻时的自己脱离肉体
She claims she emerged from her body as a younger version of herself
然后开始说话
and started talking.
她记不得说了什么
She couldn't remember what was discussed.
但我确定没有差别
But I'm sure it wasn't a differential.
豪斯  认知模式识别
House, cognitive pattern recognition
是50年前有用的诊断工具
Is 50 years from being a useful diagnostic tool.
就算我们能搞到仪器
Even if we can get the equipment,
做初步映射得要几个小时
It takes hours for the initial mapping.
要是她再次癫痫发作  可能就玩完了
If she has another seizure, she could stroke out.
与此同时要是我们什么也不做  她也可能玩完
Coincidentally, She could also have a stroke if we do nothing.
我不会和一个吓坏了的母亲说
I'm not telling a mother who's scared out of her mind
魔幻戏法是我们最好的选择
That our best shot is a magic trick.
不是魔幻的  是试验性的
It's not magical. It's experimental.
就像当年的便后洗手一样
Just like washing your hands after pooping once was.
理论角度而言  不是我们最好的选择
And technically, it's not our best shot.
我相当肯定是我们唯一的选择
I'm pretty sure it's our only shot.
好极了
Perfect.
那么  福曼  去拿她的知情同意书
So, Foreman, go get her consent.
其他人下楼到认知科学实验室
The rest of you go down to the cog sci lab.
仪器应该已经在那里了
Equipment should already be there.
我随后就到
I'll catch up.
多谢邀请
Thanks for the invite.
我不太确定我喜欢医院食物
I'm not sure I'm up for the hospital food.
不错  因为我没计划共进午餐
Good, 'cause I wasn't planning on lunch.
当你看录像剪辑的时候
While you watch video clips,
电脑会记录你的大脑如何处理图像
A computer maps how your brain processes the images.
要多久呢
How long will it take?
6小时  不过这还只是准备工作
Six hours. But that's really just the prep.
一旦电脑了解她如何处理信息
Once the computer maps how she processes the information,
我们会将她半麻
We'll put her under twilight sedation,
用同样的仪器监测她的潜意识思维活动
Use the same equipment to monitor her unconscious thoughts.
顺利的话  能提供一个基本影像 关于她脑袋里所发生的事情
Hopefully, it'll spit out a very basic video of whatever's going on in her head.
然后那个能告诉你们什么呢
And what will that tell you?
希望  能给我们 你大脑中问题所在线索
Hopefully, it'll give us a clue as to where your brain thinks the problem is.
好多希望啊
A lot of "Hopefullys".
有副作用吗
Could it hurt her?
我们现在也没有其它诊断结果
We're at a diagnostic dead end.
必须试一下
We've got to try something.
这比吃午餐好很多
This is much better than lunch.
是啊
I agree.
你怎么想到这个的
What made you think of this?
我想你
I missed you.
不  我是说
No, I...I mean this...
在车里  在停车场
Car, in the parking lot.
我只是不想觉得你不是第一次这么做
I just don't like feeling like maybe this isn't the first time you've done this.
确实是第一次
It's the first.
我爱你  你是知道的对吗
I love you. You know that, right?
我知道
Yes.
你要信任我
I want you to be able to trust me.
我也希望  但是
And I want to, but...
天黑之后就没有灵感了
Inspiration point doesn't open till after dark.
真正的魔幻戏法就要开始了
Got a real cool magic show about to start.
另外  我要经常查你的岗
Also, I'm gonna need to check your spare.
艾比  你可以想一些细节的东西吗
Abby, can you think of something specific?
比如什么
Like what?
不要紧  一些简单的影像
Doesn't matter. Just make it a single image.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
尼克在打棒球
About Nick playing baseball.
天啊
Holy crap.
太神了
That's amazing.
是的  现在我们需要做的就是研究她的潜在意识
Yeah. Now all we have to do is read her subconscious
希望它完全合理
And hope that it's completely rational
然后去医学院
And went to med school.
你觉得很兴奋吗
Does anything get you excited?
请问有什么能帮你的
Can I help you with something?
我希望你可以介绍一下 这张餐桌
Yes. I was wondering if you could tell meA little bit about this dining table.
它原材料是木头  你可以在上面吃饭
It's made of wood, and you eat off it.
你是按厂商佣金推销的吗
So you're paid by commission?
这只是家具
It's furniture.
如果看到喜欢的告诉我
Find something you like. Let me know.
我来开单
I'll ring it up.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
这个不是我要的
Okay, that's...that's not the one.
这件非常不错我可以给你介绍一下
That is a remarkable collection, If I can show it to you.
我是加布里埃尔
I'm Gabriella.
我想找一张满意的餐桌
I'm really just looking for a nice dining-room table.
我知道  你很另类
I see. You're daring.
是的  有时候但是
Yes, I do that sometimes, But...
现在你为什么觉得我另类
Right now why am I daring?
你不拘泥于规则
You're not constrained by rules.
还有其它吸引你的阳台家具吗
What else attracts you in the patio section?
等等  这是户外用的阳台家具吗
Wait, this is a patio tab... for outside?
我们花了一个多小时
Well, it's taken us just over an hour
就为了看她的无聊意识吗
To prove that she has a very boring subconscious.
有人说过你很扫兴吗
Anyone ever tell you you can be a real buzzkill?
有
Yes.
星星
Stars?
可能是条纹
Maybe that's a stripe?
是天空
It's the sky.
她在想月亮
She's thinking about the moon
星星和天空
And the stars and the sky.
她要去斯坦福学物理
She's going to Stanford to study physics.
所以想象天空没什么好意外的
It's not a big revelation that she'd think about the sky.
星星可能是白血球
Or star could be a white blood cell.
白血病
Leukemia?
那是谁
Who's that?
他爸爸
Her dad?
他在她8岁时去世
He died when she was eight.
怎么死的
What did daddy die of?
私人飞机坠毁  毫无联系
Private-plane crash... no connection.
星星  月亮  天空
Stars, moon, sky,
白血球  心脏瓣膜黑洞或者肛门
White blood cells, heart valves, Black holes, or anus
或者成百万通向身体的通道
Or a million other circular passageways into the body
还有她爸爸
And her dad.
你觉得是什么意思
What do you think it means?
她喜欢上学 有恋父情结
She likes school, And she has daddy issues...
两者对我们都毫无帮助
Neither of which helps us.
我们现在做什么  重新开始吗
So now what do we do? Start over?
显然我们错过什么了
We obviously missed something.
肝脏呢
What about the liver?
左脚趾呢
What about her left toe?
对不起
Sorry.
我以为我们在猜身体哪个部分
I thought we were randomly picking out body parts
和她的症状没有关系
That had nothing to do with her symptoms.
肝脏是负责蛋白质
Liver's responsible for proteins,
免疫反应和造红血球的
Immunological effects, production of red blood cells.
或许可以解释肺部问题和幻觉
Might be able to explain the lungs, The hallucinations.
但没有解释不通主动脉夹层
Not the aortic dissection.
同样  肾脏在衰竭
Kidneys are also failing.
还有性疾病  可以解释解主动脉夹层
We add in polycystic disease, could explain the dissection.
一个完善的推测
So that's one imperfect theory,
加一个混乱的推测
Plus a rare complication of a second theory,
给了我们一个完整的解释
Which gives us a complete explanation.
你想到什么了福曼
Don't polish the notion, Foreman.
松果腺钙化
Pineal gland is calcified.
青春期之后
It's supposed to be calcified.
都会钙化
Happens after puberty.
如果它里面有肿瘤呢
What if it's obscuring a tumor?
那里面是我们唯一看不到的地方
It's the only place we couldn't look inside.
用三倍特斯拉旋转反射核磁共振成像
Get a better look at her pineal gland
再去检查一下她的松果腺
With three tesla fast spin echo mri.
你来我办公室是因为要买家具的事
You're pacing my office 'cause you're buying furniture?
不  我来你办公室
No, I'm pacing your office
是因为我天生不会买家具
Because I'm physically incapable of buying furniture.
是为Amber的老地方买吗
For Amber's old place?
是的
Yeah.
需要买些新的
It needs some new...
我知道你买了我想要的地方
I know you bought the place I wanted.
你是个混蛋  继续
You're a jerk. Let's move on.
请一个室内设计师
Hire a decorator.
我想自己来
I'm supposed to find me.
你不如背包穿越欧洲
Backpack through Europe.
我知道你很难相信
I know it's hard to believe,
但你应该了解你自己多过了解家具吧
But you know what says even more About who you are than your furniture?
事实上你让豪斯教你怎么买家具
The fact that you are letting House tell you how to buy furniture.
打电话给Beatrice
Call Beatrice.
核磁共振没有透析出 松果腺异常
Mri revealed no remarkable features on her pineal gland.
只是乳酸脱氢酶异酵素水平稍微偏高
But there were slightly elevated levels of lactate dehydrogenase isoenzymes.
如果有过敏反应我们应该怎么办
Which we would expect to see if there was an allergic reaction happening.
不可能过敏
There's definitely no allergy.
寄生虫呢
Parasite?
这种中东的寄生虫
There's this middle eastern parasite...
你就这么想被反驳得无话可说吗
How exactly do you want to be shot down?
事实摆在那儿
On the basis of the fact
她从没踏入过中东的方圆六千里之内
that she's never been within 6,000 miles of the middle east,
而我们所做的所有
or on the basis of the fact that all our scans
测验和尿检都呈阴性
And urine samples came back clean?
而她依旧在衰竭一个系统接着一个系统
And yet she's still failing, system after system.
我们要不然就在尸检台上找到答案
So either we find the answer at autopsy
要不然就
Or...
什么
What?
我不知道
I got nothin'.
我得出去一趟
I was gonna head out.
要是有问题  你会呼我吧
If there's any change, I assume you'll page me?
你有外遇吗
Are you having an affair?
你妻子不敢问你这个问题而我却敢问
Does it bother you that your wife doesn't have the guts to actually ask that question,
这让你感到烦恼吗
and I do?
两边都是
On both ends, yes.
不同之处在于  答案不会让我害怕
Difference is, I'm not afraid of the answer.
而且我会相信你
And I might believe you.
我没外遇
I'm not having an affair.
但你想搞外遇
But you want to.
我不想
No, I don't.
我不想再那样过日子了
I'm through living like that.
为什么
Why?
怎么  你还是到了那点子上吗
What, you finally got to the point
连只比你岁数的一半大七岁的女孩也不够年轻了吗
where half your age plus seven just isn't young enough?
晚点跟你说
Talk to you later, house.
还是说你实在已经老得足以做他们的
Or is it because you now really are old enough to be their--
那个爸爸
The dad.
他会出差吗
Does he travel for work?
你说什么  他会吗
What do you mean, "Does he"?
他十年前就死了
He died almost ten years ago.
不是她的  她男友的
Not hers, her boyfriend's.
她幻觉里的那个人是他
He's the one in her visions.
我是你儿子女友的医生
I'm your son's girlfriend's doctor.
这头衔可真够长的
Oh. It's a mouthful,
但应该没有你的复杂
But probably not as tricky as your title.
好吧  艾比会好起来吗
Um, okay. Is abby gonna be all right?
你经常旅游吗
Do you travel a lot?
对啊  我做食品进口生意  怎么了
Yeah, I have a food-import business. Why?
你去过哪儿
Where'd you go?
哪里都去
All over--
法国  意大利 地中海地区  怎么了
France, italy, the mediterranean. Why?
我认为你令她感染了寄生虫
I think you exposed her to a parasite.
但检测里什么都没显示啊
I thought the scans didn't show any.
因为她什么都没有得
Because she doesn't have any.
-但你刚才说  -这很酷
- But you just said... - It's cool.
我的猜想是她的身体能杀死寄生虫
My theory is that her body was able to kill off the parasite,
但却没办法清除它们的外壳
But what it couldn't do was get rid of the shell,
这在检测里无法显示
which doesn't show up on the scans.
那些微型的垃圾
That little piece of microscopic garbage
引起了过敏反应叫做小脑血吸虫
set off an allergic reaction Called cerebellar
迟发性过敏症
schistosomiasis delayed hypersensitivity allergy,
或者说cusdehaaa
Or cusdehaaa.
治疗痛苦而充满风险  但绝对能治
Risky, unpleasant treatment, but completely curable.
好吧  那很棒
Well, that's fantastic.
你这么想不是吗
You'd think so, wouldn't you?
只有一点
Only thing is,
你和你儿子的女朋友睡过吗
did you ever have sex with your son's girlfriend?
你该死的在问些什么鬼东西
Where the hell do you get off asking--
闭嘴
Shut up.
听着  不确定的话我就不能治疗
See, I can't treat this unless I can confirm it,
而性接触是感染
and the only way she could have been exposed
这一寄生虫的唯一途径
to this parasite is sexually,
意味着除非你承认和她睡过不然她很快就要死了
which means she's gonna die very soon unless you admit that you slept with her.
爸
Dad?
发生什么事
What's going on?
糟糕了
Gee, this is bad,
你得二选一了  是让她死掉呢
because you now have to choose between her living
还是把这公诸于众呢
and the truth becoming public.
实话说  在这种情况下
And frankly, given what the truth is,
这真是困难的选择
it's a tough call.
你们分手了
You'd broken up.
她在哭
She was crying.
你女友不是对你的精液过敏
Your girlfriend is not allergic to your semen.
她对你父亲精液中的埃及寄生虫过敏
She's allergic to the egyptian parasite swimming around in your dad's semen.
你和艾比上床了吗
You slept with Abby?
我醉了
I was drunk.
我们都
We both...
没什么好解释  理论说来这是合法的
No need to explain. Technically, she was legal.
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait. Wait. Wait!
嘿
Hey!
全盘考虑的话
All things considered,
其实这是好消息
it's actually great news.
你觉得怎么样
So what do you think?
你懦弱地退缩了  找了个装修公司
You wussed out, and you used a decorator.
我为什么就不能这样
Why can't that be me--
做个热爱装修公司的懦夫呢
the wuss who loves decorators?
因为你就不是
'cause it's not.
好吧  我不是
Okay. It's not.
但再全还回去了  我不能一直这么做
But don't return it. I can't keep doing this.
你必须这样
You have to.
你不能一直让别人来定义你
You can't keep letting other people define you.
不会是另一头大象吧
Not another elephant.
装修公司没挑这个
Decorator didn't pick this.
你得自己买防尘罩
You're gonna have to buy your own cape.
我喜欢这所代表的你  威尔森
I like what this says about you, Wilson.
我不记得他来过我们婚礼
I don't remember him at the wedding.
你呢
Do you?
婚礼上大部分人我都不记得了
I don't remember most of the people who were at our wedding.
所以我想
Which is why...
我该求我一生挚爱下嫁于我
I thought I'd ask the love of my life to marry me.
我们已经结婚了
We're already married.
我想做得更好
I want to be better at it.
这真漂亮
Oh, it's beautiful.
你跟他说什么了
What'd you tell him?
那并不代表她不爱他
That it doesn't mean she doesn't love him.
他这就接受了吗
And he bought it?
是真的
It's true.
你妻子同意了吗
Your wife say yes?
你怎么知道
How did you know--
西子捧心  东施效颦
Monkey see, monkey do.
至少他以年轻愚蠢做借口
At least he has the young and stupid excuse.
她同意了
She said yes.
恭喜
Good for you.
谢谢
Thank you.